Guide to the Gustave Gimon Collection of French Political Economy: general ephemera, 1669-1880
Department of Special Collections
- Insurance Ephemera
  - la Compagnie Royale des Assurances réunies Statuts de la Compagnie Royale des Assurances réunies Manuscript. 9 p. n.d., Statutes of the insurance company. Includes 7 Titles, 39 Articles. (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - La Nationale La Nationale ( Ancienne Compagnie Royale) Compagnie d'Assurances à primes contre l'Incendie... Conditions Générales La Nationale. in-folio and manuscript 1863, Insurance contract for fire insurance. Details, additional articles, and signatures in manuscript. (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - la Societé d'Assurance Mutuelles de Valence Statuts de la Societé d'Assurances Mutuelles Contre la Grêle,... Valence, Imprimerie de Marc Aurel 1829, Statutes of the insurance company. Includes 136 articles. (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - A.P. Julienne Belair Convention Nationale. Memoire sur les Assurances Agricoles... Paris, Imprimerie nationale. Imprimé par ordre de la Convention Nationale 1793, On the advantages of establishing an insurance company for the harvest, for multiplying the foods, making them less expensive, and promoting the sufficiency of the existing quantities. (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - De Courcy, Alfred Des Assurances Agricoles, par Alfred de Courcy Paris, Ch. Douniol & Aug. Fontaine. 47 p. 1857, On agricultural insurance. (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Norwich Union. Norwich Union. Compagnie Anglaise. Assurances contre l'Incendie. Norwich Union. 1826, Fire insurance policy for the Paris properties of the Duc de Vantado[cio]. Print and manuscript. Signed by officers of insurance company. (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - De Courcy, Alfred Des Assurances Agricoles, par Alfred de Courcy Paris, Ch. Douniol & Aug. Fontaine. 47 p. 1857, On agricultural insurance. (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Nous, les assureurs ci-dessous signes... Chez Larre, Courtier brevete, Bordeaux. 2 p, 1 leaf, in-folio and manuscript. 1784, Insurance contract for M. Raimond & Cie., for the merchandise carried on a ship departing from Bordeaux for Guadeloupe, Saint-Domingue, and Senegal. (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Compagnie d'Assurances Générales Compagnie d'Assurances Générales contre l'Incendie... Police. Conditions Générales. Compagnie d'Assurances Générales 1820, Fire insurance policy, with printed conditions on 1 side, manuscript "conditions particulieres" on verso. For a marchand epicier of Troyes. (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Workers' papers
  - la Communauté des Marchands & Maîtres Ouvriers Fabricants en Etoffes...Lyon ... la Communauté des Marchands & Maîtres Ouvriers Fabricants en Etoffes... certifions & attestions avoir inscrit au Registre des Maîtres, Guillaume Jacquin In folio and manuscript 1781, Certificate proclaiming one Guillaume Jacquin as "Compagnon de Lyon" (Box 1, Folder 35)